

# **PROFILE**

I am a motivated and hardworking Electrical and Electronics Engineering (EEE) graduate with a keen interest in robotics and embedded systems. My diverse skill set and professional experience make me a versatile individual who can handle multiple tasks with ease and excel under pressure. I am currently conducting research and working on projects in the field of robotics and embedded systems, where I apply my creativity and problem-solving skills to develop innovative solutions.

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

To utilize my technical expertise and contribute to innovative research and development initiatives in a dynamic and challenging environment. Seeking opportunities to apply my skills, collaborate with diverse teams, and make a valuable contribution towards achieving organizational goals.

# MD. RAFIQUL ISLAM

**Embedded System Engineer Electrical Electronic Engineering Graduate** 

+88-01628980089

irafiqul302@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rafixlam/



sites.google.com/diu.edu.bd/rafixlam



B-83/2, Digir Chala, Chandona, Joydebpur, Gazipur 1702, Dhaka

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**EMBEDDED SYSTEM ENGINEER. INTERN** 

FEB 2023 - MAY 2023

ROBODOC LIMITED

ROBODOC LIMITED, A SISTER CONCERN OF APPNAP TECHNOLOGIES LTD. WEB LINK https://appnap.io/ || https://robodocbd.com/

CIRCUIT/PCB DESIGNER **TEAM LEADER, SEP 2022**  FABLAB DIU - MULTI-DISCIPLINARY FABRICATION LABORATORY HEQEP FOR TRANSFORMING INNOVATIVE IDEAS FROM MIND TO MARKET.

WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/yeyptew3

**TECHNICAL** SUPPORT ASS. JUN 2021-DEC 2021

**GOINNOVIOR TECHNOLOGY (INTERNSHIP)** 

CYBERSECURITY & NETWORK ENGINEERING WEB LINK http://goinnovior.com/

**COM. SERVICE TECHNICIAN** MAR 2018-OCT 2019

TRUST COMPUTER SERVICES

COMPUTER SALES & SERVICE SHOP WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/2p94kpyr

#### **EDUCATION**

**BSc in EEE** STARTED IN JAN 2019 - DEC 2022

BSc in ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (DIU)

**CGPA - 3.65** 

**NANOTECHNOLOGY** 

NOV 2022 - DEC 2022

**FACULTY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY** 

ASSAM DOWN TOWN UNIVERSITY - INDIA

EXCHANGE PROGRAM - REFERRED BY DIU INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS

# TRAINING

MICROCHIP VLSI **DESIGN WORKSHOP** 

ORGANIZED BY "BANGLADESH HI-TECH PARK AUTHORITY". "CADENCE DESIGN SYSTEMS" AND "UIU"

WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/bdetxba8

**ROBOTICS & EMBEDDED SYSTEMS TRAINING**  **CREATIVE IT INSTITUTE** 

2020

YOUTH SOCIAL **LEADERSHIP TRAINING**  ORGANIZED BY "NEW YORK UNIVERSITY", "THE UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO", "USAID" WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/4jn2nt22

# **ACHIEVEMENT**

**BEST BRAND AMBASSADOR**  IFFF SPAVE 6.0

AMONG ALL THE IEEE STUDENT BRANCHES IN BANGLADESH WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/2p8bt7cb

**RUNNERS UP ON ROBO RACE**  **MECCELERATION 2019 ISLAMIC UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY (IUT)** WEB LINK https://tinyurl.com/2z24vp3y

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

**ROBOTICS PCB DESIGN** C Programming Lan. **PYTHON** 3D DESIGN (Fusion 360) VLSI (BASIC) VHDL (BASIC) VERILOG (BASIC) **GRAPHIC DESIGN** 

# **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

**ARDUINO PROTEUS ALTIUM EAGLE** OrCAD MATI AR **CADENCE TOOLS MICROWIND SYSTEMVERILOG** ADOBE PHOTOSHOP MICROSOFT OFFICE GOOGLE WORKSPACE -

# INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

**LEADERSHIP** ANALYTICAL **TFAMWORK** PROBLEM SOLVING MENTORING **NEGOTIATION** 

#### **COMMUNITY & VOLUNTEER SERVICE**



#### Student Ambassador

Hult Prize at Daffodil International University
May 2019 – Present • 1 yr 10 mos



#### Student Ambassador

**IEEEXtreme** 

May 2023 - Present · 2 mos



## Campus Ambassador

IEEE SPAVe 4.0

Nov 2019 - Jan 2020 • 3 mos



# Ambassador IEEE PES DAY 2023 Feb 2023 - May 2023 · 4 mos



# Community Ambassador

Riseup Labs

Oct 2020 - Present • 5 mos



#### **Event Ambassador**

Interactive Cares

May 2022 - Jun 2022 - 2 mos



Campus Ambassador Robo Tech valley

Dec 2020 – Present • 3 mos



International Protocol Volunteer

Association of Universities of Asia and the Pacific - AUAP

Oct 2022 - Present - 9 mos



Volunteer

Bangladesh Innovation Forum

Mar 2019 – Present • 2 yrs

## **CLUB ENGAGEMENT**

**IEEE DIU STUDENT BRANCH** 

**SECRETARY** 

Altium

**Autodesk** 

**Autodesk Fusion 360** 

FABLAB DIU

TEAM LEADER, CIRCUIT/PCB DESIGNER

**EEE CLUB** 

JOB CAREER AND INDUSTRY COLLABORATION SECRETARY OF EEE CLUB, DIU

**ROBOTICS CLUB** 

MEMBER OF ROBOTICS CLUB, DIU

**CPC CLUB** 

MEMBER OF COMPUTER & PROGRAMMING CLUB, DIU

# **CERTIFICATION**

LINK

CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL
YOUTH SOCIAL LEADERSHIP

Kaspersky Embedded Sys. Security New York University LINKEDIN FACEBOOK

PCB DESIGN COURSES

GRABCAD

DIGITAL MANUFACTURING

BEHANCE

INTEGRATED CAD/CAM/CAE

WEBSITE

CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL
DRIVE LINK FOR VIEW CERTIFICATE

**NSE 2 Network Security Associate - Fortinet** 

https://tinyurl.com/yechl6bv

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafixlam/ https://www.facebook.com/lamrafix/ https://grabcad.com/md.rafiqul.islam-4

https://www.behance.net/rafixlam

https://sites.google.com/diu.edu.bd/rafixlam

# REFERENCE

DR. TAMA FOUZDER

ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

**DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY** 

PHONE: +88-01747744721

 $\label{lem:emale:lem:ema$ 

**MOUMITA KABIR ANANNA** 

EMBEDDED SYSTEM ENGINEER AT ROBODOC LIMITED

PHONE: +880 1765-689015

EMAIL: anannakabirmk@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/moumita-kabir-ananna-87b621139/

## **CONTACT INFO**



+88-01628980089



www.linkedin.com/in/rafixlam/



rafiqul33-822@diu.edu.bd



sites.google.com/diu.edu.bd/rafixlam



B-83/2, Digir Chala, Chandona, Joydebpur, Gazipur 1702, Dhaka